that thing is
the phenomenon that we feel we can't
live up to what we
thought we could
do or we can't live up to a promise or
if the stress does not come from
ourselves which those two would be
examples of then the stress often comes
from the outside of course if there is
the imminence imminent threat of
impact of injury of harm of even death
from the outside that of course causes a
stress reaction in our biology as well
how does stress Express itself
physically by creating
biochemicals
at an amount that is not normal what we
all know about the adrenaline that gets
increased right we all know about the
cortisol that gets increased and then
there's another one called and I keep
messing this up it's
endoadrenaline is that
let me just check here
there we go
yeah and then there's there's all kinds
of other chemicals
um that we
oh norepinephrine and
adrenocardio tropic
um compounds so all these we've found
names for all these particular molecules
um but the point is that the the
physical biochemical reaction to
emotional and mental stressors whether
they come from our own disappointment in
our own performance or whether they come
from the outside
forced Upon Us by threats
um these biochemical reactions are so
real that they cannot be denied you know
30 40 years ago people would say oh it's
all in your mind you know just calm down
you'll be fine and then we found that
there are literally of course biological
alterations taking place in our
physiology
no
let's list a few more things that cause
stress and how stress expresses itself
um
of course we all know that when we have
to pass a test or when we have to meet a
deadline when we have to
reach or or are backstage for a
performance
um all those situations create
extra adrenaline just to give you an
example of the more fun version you know
every time
um I would be on a film Stat or back
film set or backstage before a
performance
um my entire physiology would change for
example we were once shooting a scene
That was supposed to be
in a in a warm climate in a summertime
climate but it was really really cold
outside and I was in this light little
dress and
um but the moment camera camera rolled
there's just so much adrenaline in you
that you do not feel cold I was very
warm and very fine
and it's only after those
um extra adrenaline subside that
the body will have the reaction of oh
I'm cold
foreign
which is another phenomenon so there is
a positive element of course in creating
those extra
chemicals that help us survive an
imminent threat for example or a
situation like that
but when that situation lasts longer
than a short stressor period of time
that's when it becomes all kinds of
other things such as anxiety right we
literally call it anxiety so stress that
is positive is it necessary thing for a
short event becomes something that eats
away at us over time if it stays there
and we get into a constant state of
anxiety where we can't
oh relax
um
I'm sure everybody has experienced this
kind of situation in their lifetime one
way or another
so that we know what it feels like but
often
we just don't know how to possibly get
out of it because it's as if because
it's so biochemical as if our body has
decided to produce all this extra stuff
all these chemicals that override our
brain literally flush our brain so that
we have very little power to
put that back into place right when it's
biochemical there seems to be harder to
to
um I don't want to use the word mitigate
all the time but to disperse that again
and while there are methods of doing
that
the
fact that we all want to live we all
want to
continue living a meaningful life is
seems to be the biggest driver of this
need to
create the stress that then allows us to
survive yet the next stressful situation
yes that and we get into this constant
stress
being
so
the desire to survive the desire to
perform well the desire to
help somebody else survive of course
this becomes really really strong when
our loved ones are involved right when
there's a threat on our loved one's life
and or situation
we become stressed because especially
when we don't have a way to immediately
help that situation which is another
interesting phenomenon once we're
actively involved in changing the
stressing situation
the stress goes away because then we
become active and use the extra
adrenaline and cortisol and all the
other extra chemicals to
put energy out there to change the
situation
and because in today's world
we so often don't have a way to get
actively involved to change the
situation
that the stress persists an example
in the old days we didn't have cell
phones
Etc we've
worked the car was stuck in a in a snow
bench this is again an example from my
life I was a teenager a young teenager
you know there was no cell phone help
you know 9-1-1 or whatever you know so
we had to dig ourselves out of that snow
pile where this the car was literally
halfway down the the slope and we had to
actively you know go crawl up on the
street and and try to stop another
vehicle and explain what happened and
get involved with the farmer who came
with the tractor and a big metal rope
and pulled the car back out when we have
a mean of getting means of getting
actively involved in changing the
situation that causes us the stress this
stress dissipates
because we're using that adrenaline for
the
handling of the changing of the
situation
and then we become actually we get
dopamine out of it we get serotonin in
the end you know oh we've got said done
wow
that was a challenge right that was
something and now we we're actively
participating and getting it done
but when your stress comes from some out
there forces suddenly raising all the
prices and you go into a store and you
can't afford the things you want to buy
for for food and and or your business
Etc when the stress comes from your car
breaking down and you don't have that
collaboration of other people helping
you out you don't have that farmer who's
coming with a tractor but you sit there
helplessly
so stress is very deeply connected with
helplessness
does that make sense
we don't think of it that way right
Christine gives it the thumb up thumbs
up
um
so when we are not in our
power to
impact the situation that causes us
stress
it impacts us the more and we feel
degraded by it because we can't actively
change it we feel disempowered by it
because we can't actively
change it we feel inadequate we feel we
have let ourselves down let other people
down let our loved ones down
Etc because we don't find a way to
actively change the situation
many examples come to mind of course as
I'm talking about this because so many
times
in the modern world you know all we have
is this thing and I mean even though I
just actually actively before we went
live here before we recorded actively
was able to change my son's situation
who had left his driver's license at
home but needs it to enter his job
situation
so I was able to change that situation
by
by this device and giving him his
driver's license as a photo right and
that can work
so finding a way to
actively getting involved
will
Abate is another good word and
lower the chemicals produced in your
body
and therefore will lower the anxiety
will lower the stress
and we can do this
yeah of course by actively participating
and sometimes it is very difficult to
actively participate when the stress is
for example Financial right and you have
to find a way to bring those dollars in
so that the situation can change
and that's when
one of the ways is to just go out and do
anything you can to earn extra dollars
you know for many of us
that concept is just really difficult
you know when we're Highly Educated
we're very established we've made
hundreds of thousands of dollars in a
year before and suddenly we are here in
a situation where the middle class is
shrinking and our positioning is being
degraded and we have this status thing
that
we think we need to be and present
ourselves and have Etc in a certain
manner
then we're causing extra stress by that
imagery imagery by that image we have of
our self and how we need to be in the
world
so there's another reason
why we have so much stress because
we can't we find it hard to admit
that
it must be our fault right because why
aren't we able to do what we used to do
now
even though intellectually we completely
comprehend that the world has changed in
a way that
what we used to do doesn't work in the
same manner anymore
and adjusting to
those requirements is another way of
again getting actively involved even if
that actively involved means
signing up for
I don't know writing content for
somebody's blog post or somebody's
website or whatever it is you know for
50 bucks or 100 bucks just to actively
do something about the financial
situation you're in or like my son you
know he's actually a journalist but
journalism is not very
well paid and or it's also a dangerous
profession in so many ways
um
who
drives for money right
so
that adjustment and not allowing it to
mean that we feel that degradation
is in so many ways the trick
now
um
I wanted to speak also to this idea of
the Mind
and the mind cause illness
and our emotional
yeah whatever that is
cause illness
because of course in modern medicine you
know it's all just biological stuff but
they have to admit more and more that oh
yes
if the stress is not something that is
physically somebody hitting you over the
head or somebody kicking you in the back
that causes an injury and a chemical
reaction but if it is something that is
indeed
coming from an intellectual or
intelligent understanding of a situation
that is told us for example you know the
day that your boss walks in and says
well
we don't need you don't come back on
Monday
right when I first heard that that that
is even possible in the United States
after you know when I came from actually
I came from Zimbabwe and then Europe or
both countries I was flabbergasted that
that is even possible but
the impact that I can see in people and
that I imagine and of course
um yeah seeing people around me I'm not
on wood it hasn't really happened to me
like that but
that of course is an entirely
mental emotional process processing that
information and realizing the
consequences it will have in our
physical existence paying the rent or
the mortgage or the car payment or the
food for the kids or do we have to
cancel the trip or all of that
impacts us mentally emotionally and then
the body reacts actually the body
doesn't just take much time to react it
reacts immediately with cold sweat or
with
weird feelings it can also react
immediately with uh bowels releasing
everything that was ever in there it
feels like I have had that happen to me
when I had to close down my business my
Factory in particular my food factory
so
there are all kinds of ways in which
stress impacts us physically and I want
to elaborate a little bit more on that
but it is
almost always well that's what we call
stress today it's always that our mind
perceives something understands
something and then the body reacts
because there is no denying anymore that
of course everything that happens in
your mind soul brain heart emotional
setup
has a reflection
or a strong mirror in your physical
existence
and reversely of course we're not
talking about that today but every
physical injury or alteration
will have a strong mental impact
and keeping those two
balancing each other is therefore also
one of our tasks in today's discussion
so that
calming down your physical reaction when
stress comes from the outside
is something that we need to train and
can work on
and reversely not allowing physical
damage for example from poisoning from
exposure to from food poisoning even you
know or exposure to chemicals or
um or physical damage you know we break
an arm and a leg or we have a car
accident
Etc so physical damage
um not allowing that to impact our
mental emotional state
is the other thing
that we're not so much talking about
today but that
that again confirms
how closely those two are connected
my bad
and we want to understand that of course
when we talk about stress we talk about
our mental emotional well-being and how
we can handle those informations those
situations that impose stress Upon Our
being
um
so yeah I wanted to make sure that we
understand that there is no such thing
as separating completely
the emotional intellectual mind World
from the physical
biochemical world of our existence as
human beings
because we are conscious if we are
conscious
um now what does medical industry do
when you're too stressed out when people
are stressed out and they have anxiety
and there is now
um
the extra cortisol leads to
blood clots and high blood pressure and
heart disease and possibly kidney
failure Etc so all of these things can
happen
as a physical reaction to ongoing
stressors in the emotional mental Arena
so the physical impact therefore
then is treated by the medical world
with
counter chemicals right so then we dumb
down the brain to
try and mitigate the anxiety
or the
franticness or the
jitteriness
um and
what we do is we actually
disallow our own mind and soul or
being
to
overcome this stress situation to get
actively involved in changing it like we
said earlier so medication is therefore
completely counterproductive to that
stress mitigating ability that we have
by getting actively involved in changing
the situation
makes sense so
wherefore for the longest time
it has befuddled me that humans would
dumb themselves down instead of
using even more brain to find the
solution to a situation that puts things
Back in Balance
so what we do of course with all anxiety
medications
um
is exactly that we slow down
the mental ability to find Solutions
now of course
people who take those medications will
say that's not true Johanna
um we become calmer and then we can
think better and then we can find
Solutions better
yeah and that's why you're on these
medications for years and years
doesn't look like a logical answer to me
so
what do we do
oh my God it's late
um and we
all these topics are so rich right
yeah and also we could get sick from
those things as well so
yeah the medication is a big question
mark yeah yes not only I mean of course
I'm talking today about getting sick
from the stress but of course we then
also can get sick from the medication to
that is supposed to stop this this
stress and therefore it becomes a
self-perpetuating vicious cycle
um so now what do we do though when we
do get stress
sickness or sick from stress and it
expresses itself like I said in so many
ways we can get sick from
um we can get sick in the stomach that's
often the first place
where we
we have all kinds of reactions
either we get diarrhea or we start
vomiting or we just feel nauseous and
feel weak
or we
we get cramps and Bloated and you know
that all kinds of phenomena that happen
in our digestive tract as a reaction to
that extra stress and those extra
stress chemicals that suddenly show up
in the body and create Havoc
then there's like I said then there's
the whole heart Arena our heartbeat
increases
in stressed situations
our blood pressure Rises
um and
the blood flow becomes inconsistent
so that there's more likely
put off um
blood clots
and of all kinds of other heart issues
and then of course the liver and the
kidney
get interrupted in their functioning of
cleansing the blood when there is all
these extra biochemicals so and again we
often don't think about that you know
that the extra production which come
from our stress reaction to something
um will put a huge burden on those
cleansing organs right the liver
cleanses the blood the the kidney
cleanses the blood and
and when there's too much of this added
chemical load
those organs begin to fail to to process
all of that properly
so
the cleansing doesn't happen properly
um
and therefore what like what Christine
is doing right now is so important that
we again and again allow our body to
cleanse so that all the systems calm
down and we
we are in a state of
better balance between what all the
biochemistry should be in our body
um
what are the immediate
tools that we can use
to
alter this the the situation of high
stress
now when we get to the level of where
our body is physically shaking
I've been there so
it's a weird thing again you know your
body just sort of overrides your mind
and everything and it just goes like Oh
and you
you think you have absolutely no power
over it anymore with your mind
the first thing
that I would like everybody to note is
oh breathing
even if everything is shaking
and at the time I didn't know about
breathing
because a couple of breaths won't do it
it has to be 20 or more deep breaths and
you know that's why Wim Hof is so
important Wim Hof some of you may know
him
um
that 20 30 deep breaths if at all
possible if in a situation
will come down the chemical production
of the adrenaline
and the whole slew of other chemicals
that have names that are too long for me
to pull up here
when we
take those deep breaths and even in
situations where we can't just suddenly
like sit in a yoga seat and
you know do that
we can still
slow down our breath unless the nose is
completely clogged we can do that so the
first thing is breathing
and of course if we are in an ongoing
stressful situation because of for
example Financial stress or familial
stress where one of our children or
loved ones is in a stressful situation
that we don't really have a solution for
and it Bears on us
then
again
the breathing is the first thing
the next thing would be if at all
possible
get actively involved in
a solution it may not even be the
solution to this problem that causes the
stress but in something else that you
can solve right now find a solution get
active get actively involved in doing
something even if it's just going for a
walk and knowing in your mind or setting
your mind to
I am walking the solution will come to
me as I am walking
I do that you know when I go running a
lot and it helps me I used to
before I was running I used to go to bed
at night and say okay
I'll I will let the solution come to me
when I wake up and I'll give myself five
six days you know if it was a
life-changing situation or or decision I
had to make that was stressful
I would give myself those kind of
um to create a state
in which your decision can feel like
it's coming to you you don't have to
make it that also helps many people
because it can create too much stress
you know I have to find the solution I
have to find the solution that's not
what I mean what I mean is yet active in
trusting yourself and do something even
if it's just walking or cooking or
writing or
or
going online
looking for what other people are doing
in this situation of course that is an
Avenue that I would certainly use now
that we have these tools
and while they may not as work as well
as the calling the farmer with the truck
to pull us out of the snow
they still work because we're actively
getting involved in finding a solution
um
another point that I wanted to make that
is very important in
lessening also the possibility of stress
coming back is
knowing or creating a community around
us and it doesn't have to be all close
by by
the human beings with whom we can be
honest enough
truly honest enough
to share what is stressing us because
talking about it already helps a huge
amount
talking about the anxieties talking
about the stressors already helps that's
why we have so much therapy what the
therapy is missing though is getting
actively involved in the solution
so not that I'm bashing therapists very
important parts but if they're not
helping a person getting active
then the failing ultimately and of
course unfortunately our Industries are
built so that people have to come back
for more and back for more because
otherwise the therapist can't pay their
bills and it's going to be under stress
that's the conundrum and the crazy world
that we live in
so
in fact
and this is now the big arch and then
we're going to get into a couple of
questions
um our entire social system
is built on stress if you want why
because
you have to pay to be alive
because the monetary system is built on
debt
every time
money is ushered whether it's digital
money or paper money or any money
doesn't really matter
it creates a debt
and what does debt do to you her stress
because you're going to have to pay it
back and you don't know how otherwise
you you know you you wouldn't stress
over it but debt in and of itself is the
form of an externally created stress a
stressor on you to pay it back
and since our entire world is based on
debt and based on
the the need to
monetarily fund Your Existence all the
time
wherever you are you have to pay to be
alive
in today's world and that alone of
course is an enormous stress you can't
just go out into the woods and pick
berries and roots and fruits and
and live there's no Place anymore in the
world that isn't owned by anybody so you
are in a constant stressor situation
how do we deal with that
I deal with that by saying okay that's
the phase humanity is going through I'm
trying not to play the game and say I'm
gonna wing this whichever way I have to
to make it less stressful for me but
guess what it doesn't always work so I
still crash sometimes because I have
bitten off too much for myself to
complete it right
um
and of course when you get actively
involved in finding the solutions you
may also bite off too much
and not get quite there and you have to
allow yourself to
we Orient yourself and find the actual
solution
so
rounding it out we live in stress in
this world and it is upon us to find
ways in community to support each other
to know that it helps a lot when we help
each other overcome the stressors
that we respectively are experiencing at
different times often you know we have
these High Times where everything seems
to be going great and you know we are in
love and we you know have great
communication with our friends and
children
or parents
but then there are the times where oops
it didn't work out oh the check didn't
come in uh
the rent was raised the mortgage the
this and that and the other
tree fell on the roof for that matter
so
so much for the presentation and
let us collaborate on finding ways to
overcome the stressors by becoming
active in creating the solutions for our
own life and for that of our loved ones
and others and the world ultimately also
all right and of course
I would be remiss if I didn't announce
that I am offering a 12-month course
that helps has helped hundreds of people
get from a to z in their next mission in
life so that there's activity at all
times in
pushing us forward or in
pushing is not the right word
in
self-driving us forward into that better
balance between the stressors and the
solutions
all right what are the questions what
have I left out surely are you still
with us
okay maybe you're not present and Ed are
you still with us do you want to type
something into the chat or unmute
yourself for a minute I can't hear you
because you're muted
and Christine certainly chime in
anybody you just
unmute yourself and talk and I will
let you in
maybe you could talk about how stress
and inflammation
um
you know can
you know when can impact the other
oh absolutely yes so when we have that
reaction that stress reaction of the
physical body producing all this
adrenaline and cortisol Etc it also
stresses our immune system it
overburdens our immune system and
suddenly the immune system is not if
there is such a thing as a system that
we call the immune system which is
basically
the entire
apparatus the entire computer if you
will that is our body always fixing
things where something is vulnerable at
the moment
it does that all the time I've talked
about that a lot you know that constant
cell reproduction happens and when there
is too much stress
and too much of this adrenaline
production and cortisolone
and
it interrupts that repair system
then we become vulnerable we call that
you know we are our immune system is
weakened and something will hit
an inflammation will hit where our weak
spots are
now in my case inflammation will hit
just in my head space you know I will
get a nose cold and and in my chest
so that's the area in which
I react to that imbalance and that lack
of immune system repair
um other people will react with a client
of mine has migraines when that happens
right
but again
um for her it works very very well to do
the breathing to do the
um self-talk Etc that um then comes down
that inflammation literally and
prevents a severe migraine I have not
figured out how to prevent my
head inflammations about once a year
sometimes every other
um
there's of course another aspect to
[Music]
um
tag
I have your driver's license here
okay
that was the stress situation earlier
so um yeah the and and the inflammation
can happen wherever your weak spots are
like I said it could also go into
arthritis it could go into irritable
bowel syndrome it could go into so many
other ways rheumatoid arthritis like
well I already said arthritis right
um yeah
yeah here it is
okay thank you
okay as long as it worked it kind of fit
into my explanation of what causes
stress you know
foreign
well it caused you stress too right
okay so we're we're still live and we're
still talking about stress so no that's
it's all good that's it was a good
example
love you too and again what helped the
stress situation was the fact that there
was Community it was possible for my son
to call Mom and say can you quickly take
a picture of my driver's license
otherwise I can't perform the job that I
signed up to perform today
what
so there you have it the importance of
community
cannot be
negated at all
so people who are
condensually
less really truly intimately
attached with other people and I don't
mean intimate in a romantic sense but
having friendships that run deep enough
um another example just before this
Mastermind my sister called from Germany
and
we had this conversation about her
situation
and because of the
Exchange
there are
active involvements that she will begin
to mitigate her situation in her case
she wants to get more involved in
um therapy for the elderly and or the
disabled
um
good
Christine there's of course one more
element to inflammatory situations
there's also the fact that any
inflammatory situation
is a cleansing process that the body
goes through
now you could in the case of stress
connect that with the cleansing of the
excess adrenaline that is produced and
all these other chemicals that is
produced from the stressful situation
that then the inflammation will try to
clear out inflammation is always the
body's reaction to toxicity or you know
chemically imbalanced
um so that it actually wants to clean up
shop
to clean out the stuff that is wrong to
clean out the imbalance
like just imagine you know suddenly you
have like this high level of adrenaline
here now your inflammation comes in
creates higher temperatures sometimes
creates phlegm creates you know coughing
and sneezing and snot or tears and all
kinds of things or diarrhea for that
matter you know and once to
lower this level back down so that we're
even again and that creates
loss of energy because it takes a lot of
energy to have all that inflammation
going on and all that cleansing
and we feel completely like oh my God I
caught under the cold oh my God I have
another outbreak of of um asthma or or
inflammation inflammatorium
arthritis
Etc so
because the body is trying to recreate
balance it creates the mechanisms of
temperature and phlegm and extra mule
substances often also extra
lymph fluid
um white blood cells Etc you know if
it's a physical injury for example a cut
to Abate the situation to heal the
situation to get that balance back
and to also get rid of the extra
production of chemicals that we don't
need that are becoming destructive and
if we don't have this is actually
another Insight that I would like to put
here for people who think that
medication can help
or let's say allopathic medication can
help
um there is of course herbal medication
that can help
if you stop that cleansing process of
the inflammation and prevent the body
from having any inflammation you don't
allow the body to
practice and exercise its job in
recreating the balance
and therefore you further impair your
immune system you further impair your
energetic and your confidence your
energetic abilities and your confidence
that oh I can heal myself do I need to
take time am I going to be weak do I
need more sleep and all of that yes one
does and that's where we often think oh
no I'm just going to pop a couple of
pills you know and I'm going to be fine
I'm going to go back to my job I'm going
to do
but it lowers our overall energy level
and it reduces our overall ability to
self heal and therefore it reduces our
longevity it allows cancers to come in
it allows all kinds of other illnesses
the last time we talked about chronic
diseases so you know go check out that
Mastermind
all those things can sneak in when you
don't allow your body those
inflammatory cleansing periods
and while it is a reaction to the stress
it can also be seen as a healthy thing
of course does it need to be supported
absolutely you know I I'm you do you do
your food program Christine and and you
get to juicing I have my smoothies I
have my
um I have a super drink that I make that
helps this cleansing
that is ginger garlic
um
a lot of cayenne and honey raw honey so
those four elements help again that
cleansing process and make it easier on
the body we don't want the inflammation
of course to get so big that it overruns
the entire body and therefore makes the
situation worse and then it can't do the
cleaning
job that it wants to do
um does that answer your question far
too much
okay
all right
[Music]
um
now Ed I'm seeing you in here
but I am not hearing or seeing you
can you unmute I can't unmute you you
know you have to do that yourself
I can only ask you to
but you may not be on visual
okay
good we're going to do one more question
and then we're gonna wrap it up
the stress
Mastermind
all right
the I'm going to use this as a question
can exercise help
absolutely
again when you go into
exercising
what do you do
you become Physically Active
in finding Solutions even if the
solution is not directly related to the
thing that causes you stress
but you become actively involved in
empowering yourself and whether you do
it consciously or not you're empowering
your body to better be able to rebalance
and
therefore it is very very helpful to
challenge your body with an exercise
program whether it's a workout whether
it's a run whether it's going cycling
whether it's going swimming doesn't
matter but a physical challenge
that you give your body so that the
entire system because of course what
exercise does is it increases the heart
rate but for a purpose not because of an
impact that is stress that is just like
oh I don't know what to do I don't know
what to do right now you're doing
the the increase of the heart rate by
exercising and you doing the increase of
the blood flow in a positive way and
you're doing the demanding the body to
get to functioning to fill the muscle
tissue to to create balance in your
bowels Etc physical exercise does all of
that automatically that's why it's so
important
and you know many people think oh well
100 years ago nobody did exercise yes
they did what did they do
they walked to the store They Carried
heavy bags they um of course you know
they they walked to their jobs and back
and they
or they rode horses or they Etc you know
they were involved in physical activity
all day long
and we're not we're sitting in front of
our computer and that's also why
finding the active involvement in in the
solution for your stressors or the
stress that you're experiencing is so
much more important now it doesn't
automatically happen because we don't
automatically physically continue our
life
automatically physically exercise as we
would have done 100 or 200 years ago so
yes exercise is very very important and
is an absolute
component of mitigating stress
and of course you know to me
the biggest one
biggest mitigator may actually be
sitting back and saying
this is what Humanity goes through right
now
so I'm a part of that I have to go
through too
and I can get involved wherever possible
and get to the
next day the next week the next year the
next project
by doing actively what I need to do next
and again I want to invite everybody to
come work with me if you need that help
if you need that
um putting things into perspective and
finding out what for you is the next
step
so connect with me wherever you see this
um because this will go on my YouTube
channel
wherever you see this connect connect
connect or make a comment somewhere that
you like to find out more about the how
to go about things in your own life and
situation so that you can mitigate your
own
stresses
and you see for me just having talked
about it now for an hour
has meant that I feel a lot more
centered and a lot more at ease with
well this is the way everybody lives
right now
or 99.99 of the world population
because we the human beings are those
who have taken it upon themselves to
lead and again in air quotes Humanity
have created this debt and stress
situation for us all
to grow out of that there are ways we
just have to create new systems and we
have to work with each other in
communities
communicating and being there for each
other and you will see it makes a huge
difference
and me just talking about this just
realized that I need to go see X Y this
friend that friend Karen and no no no no
no no no no no and all the other friends
that I haven't seen in a while
because that is our anchor
also for mitigating the stress
love and closeness with our fellow human
beings that are in our lives and are
collaborating with us
so there you go and then your mission
will soar
all right
that's it
I'm gonna end the recording Christine if
you still want to talk for a minute
we can do that
and everybody Johannes rawfoods.com
and raw some lifeglobal.com
the two websites where you can connect
with me and find out more
and of course all over the Internet put
in Professor Johanna Sophia and you'll
find me wherever I show up on the
interwebs in different formats
ciao for now
don't let life pass you by because you
stress yourself too much
ciao